Hello

I'm Christian Gerhardt

Atlanta, GA (229) 869-0457 lieblegerhardt@gmail.com

Summary

Dedicated and enthusiastic professional with approximately 6 years of experience in full stack development. Self-motivated and highly focused on learning and providing excellent experiences for users through my skills in software development practices. Proven able to be dropped into new ecosystems and quickly adapting to the needs and requirements required for that environment. All my experience has helped me continuously hone my skills of developing my problem-solving skills through production defects, feature implementations and software/product design discussions with specific software architectures in mind. Well versed in scrum and agile practices which strengthen my collaborative skills.

Experience

October 2020 - PRESENT

T-Mobile, Atlanta, GA- Software Engineer

- Full stack development in web account management spaces
- Technical Stack:
 - o Angular
 - Typescript
 - HAPI BFF layer
 - Adobe experience manager (AEM)
 - Java
 - Spring Boot Application
 - **Maven**
- Responsibilities:
 - o On call support on rotation with other developers in group
 - Fixing production defects
 - Feature development of new business asks for the sake of improving user experiences and flows
 - Migration of legacy architecture to current state architecture
 - Lead developer on feature development projects which required attending initial meetings to determine LOEs, callout potential blockers, help determine dependencies, etc.
 - Security, Stability, Scalability work:
 - Securing our configurations and client secret keys.
 - Moving applications to MEG proxies.
 - Improving application logging for alerts and dashboards

- Fixing application performance
- Upgrading Angular to improve security
- Writing documentation and finding more improved ways to streamline technical information through better documentation and sequence diagrams.
- Merge request reviewer on our applications
- Providing support to developers by having meetings set up to have discussions for projects, triages, knowledge transfers, etc.

May 2018 - October 2020

HNTB, Atlanta, GA - Developer Intern » Application Developer I

- Started as an Intern and after a year transitioned to a full-time role where I began operating on a small team of 5. I partook in full stack development at a fast and rapid pace developing resource allocation and public outreach tools and services.
- Technical Stack:
 - Typescript
 - Vue.js
 - o Python Django Backend
 - Amazon Web Services (DBS, EC2, S3 Buckets, etc)
 - Github
- Responsibilities:
 - Writing tickets / Attending SCRUM meetings
 - Frontend and backend feature development
 - Reviewing teammates merge requests
 - Setting up / maintenance on AWS architecture
 - Managing deployments and releases
 - Attending stakeholder public outreach meetings for getting first hand experience of users using our services.

Education

2015 - 2019

Valdosta State University, Valdosta, GA− Bachelor of science – BS, Computer Science & Minor in Anthropology

- President of ACM & Member of ACM-W
- Attended multiple ICPC competitions; received an honorable mention
- Study Abroad in Belize for an Anthropology field study

Fun Facts

I enjoy rock climbing (indoor & outdoor), traveling, video games, my cat, trying new foods, coffee, spending time with family/friends and working on my 1975 Datsun 280z.